Jalerson Lima, Msc



Full-time Professor of Information Systems
Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (IFRN)
1692 Dr. Nilo Bezerra Ramalho St.

Tirol – 59015-300 Natal – RN – Brazil

Website: http://www.ifrn.edu.br

E-mails: jalerson@gmail.com | jalerson.lima@ifrn.edu.br

Homepage: http://jalerson.me TOEFL Score: 91 points

Summary

Professor of Information Systems, Software Engineering and Computer Basics at the Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte. Researcher at the Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Healthcare. Master in Systems and Computing at the Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte. Currently looking for job or PhD oportunities abroad, specially in Canada, United States, Europe or Australia.

Research Interests

Software Engineering: Empirical software engineering, collaboration-based software development, software developers productivity assessment, mining software repositories.

Classroom and Remote Education: Computer programming, software engineering concepts and practices.

Informatics in Healthcare.

Current Activities

Since 2010: Professor of Information Systems, Software Engineering and Computer Basics Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Since 2012: Researcher, Software Developer and Project Leader of Remote Healthcare Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Health (http://lais.huol.ufrn.br)
Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Previous Experience

2009 - 2010: Systems Analyst

Sync Systems (http://www.syncsistemas.com)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2009: Substitute Professor of Information Systems

Natal Campus (http://portal.ifrn.edu.br/campus/natalcentral)

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

2008 – 2009: Remote Systems Analyst Consultant

Symetrix Corp. (http://www.symetrixcorp.com/)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2005 - 2007: Scientific Initiation Researcher

Natal Campus (http://portal.ifrn.edu.br/campus/natalcentral)

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Jalerson Lima, MSc 2

2005 – 2006: Scientific Initiation Researcher

Natal Campus

Feveral University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Education

2012 – 2014: Master's degree in Systems and Computing

Department of Computing and Applied Mathematics (https://dimap.ufrn.br/en)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2008 – 2010: Specialization's degree (Post-Bachelor qualification) in Systems Engineering

Open Superior School of Brazil (<u>http://www.esab.edu.br</u>)

Vila Velha, Espirito Santo, Brazil

2004 – 2007: Bachelor's degree in Software Development

Academic Department of Management and Information Technology (http://diatinf.ifrn.edu.br)

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

Projects

2014: Macau EXPOTEC Website, PHP Project

Macau Campus

Federal Instituton of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Since 2013: Backhoe, Master's degree project developed in Java (https://github.com/jalerson/backhoe)

Department of Computing and Applied Mathematics (https://dimap.ufrn.br/en)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

2013: Nova Cruz EXPOTEC Website, PHP Project

Nova Cruz Campus

Federal Instituton of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Since 2012: Telepediatria, Ruby on Rails project (http://telepediatria.telessaude.ufrn.br)

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Health (http://lais.huol.ufrn.br)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

2012: National Observatory of Dengue, Ruby on Rails project (http://telessaude.ufrn.br/observatoriodadengue)

AFP Video: http://youtu.be/kWvhaHXv-7o

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Health (http://lais.huol.ufrn.br)

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

2011: Pau dos Ferros EXPOTEC Website, Ruby on Rails project

Pau dos Ferros Campus

Federal Instituton of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

2009 – 2010: Telepesquisa, Ruby on Rails project

Sync Systems (http://www.syncsistemas.com)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2009 – 2010: Bluesync, Java project

Sync Systems (http://www.syncsistemas.com)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2008: RFID-based projects, Java, C# and .NET projects

Ciclop

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

Jalerson Lima, MSc 3

2008: Eye of the Eagle, C# and C project *Symetrix Corp.* (http://www.symetrixcorp.com/) *Colorado Springs, Colorado, United States*

2007: Portal Conexões de Saberes, Java project

Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ifrn.edu.br)

Natal, Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil

2006: Recarcine, PHP project

Brazilian Agency of Aquaculture Development

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte (http://www.ufrn.br)

Publications

Summary published in proceedings of conferences

Development of a system to support pediatric diabetic patients using Brazilian Remote Healthcare Program

Ricardo Arrais, Jalerson Lima, Jailton Carlos, Ricardo Valentim 10th Brazilian Congress of Pediatric Endrocrinology and Metabolism, 2013

Papers in scientific journals

Dengue National Observatory - A system for dengue cases monitoring

Daniele Montenegro da Silva Barros, Philippi Sedir Grilo de Morais, Jailton Carlos de Paiva, Jalerson Raposo Ferreira de Lima, Janaína Luana Rodrigues da Silva

Journal of Technological Innovation in Healthcare, 2013

XRTPS - Extensible Real-Time Publish-Subscribe: A multicast middleware for exchanging XML-based data in real time networks

Jalerson Raposo Ferreira de Lima, Ricardo Alexsandro de Medeiros Valentim, Bruno Gomes de Araújo, João Marcos Teixeira Lacerda, Diego Rodrigues de Carvalho, Marcel da Câmara Ribeiro Dantas, Ronaldo Maia de Medeiros

HOLOS, 2011

Complete works published in proceedings of conferences

Assessing Developer Contribution with Repository Mining-based Metrics

Jalerson Lima, Christoph Treude, Fernando Figueira, Uirá Kulesza

31st International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME), 2015

Conditional Execution: A Pattern for the Implementation of Fine-Grained Variabilities in Software Product Lines

Jadson Santos, Jalerson Lima, Gleydson Lima, Uirá Kulesza, Demóstenes Sena, Felipe Pinto, Alexandre Vianna, David Pereira, Victor Fernandes

9th Latin-American Conference on Pattern Languages of Programming, 2012

Modularization of Variabilities From Software Product Lines of Web Information Systems

Demóstenes Sena, Felipe Pinto, Gleydson Lima, Jadson Santos, Jalerson Lima, Uirá Kulesza, David Pereira, Victor Fernandes, Alexandre Vianna

9th Latin-American Conference on Pattern Languages of Programming, 2012

Squid: an extensible infrastructure for analyzing software product line implementations

Alexandre Vianna, Felipe Pinto, Demóstenes Sena, Uirá Kulesza, Roberta Coelho, Jadson Santos, Jalerson Lima, Gleydson Lima

3rd International Workshop on Knowledge Oriented Product Line Engineering, 2012

Jalerson Lima, MSc 4

Patents

Telepediatria

A system to support non-specialists doctors in pediatric appointments. $\#BR\ 51\ 2013\ 001071\ 3$

Dengue National Observatory

A web-based system to support public healthcare agents to seek for proliferation spots of the *Aedes Aegypti* mosquito.

#BR 51 2013 001073 0